# JUAN DAVID GONZALEZ

# **CONTACT DETAILS**

• E-mail: gonzalezgjuand@gmail.com

• Mobile: +31 6 44 058 117

# **PROFILE**

Economist with experience in corporate credit analysis. Great experience working in teams and producing executive reports and presentations. Always motivated towards finding pragmatic solutions to common problems while striving for excellence. Proficient in English and French, both written and spoken. Good knowledge of statistical software, the Office suite as well as some programming knowledge. Currently pursuing a Master's degree in Finance at Tilburg University.

## **EXPERIENCE**

• International and Financial Institutions Credit Analyst at Bank of Bogotá

May 2017 - August 2018

## Responsibilities:

 Analysis of credit facilities and counterparty risk for domestic and international financial institutions such as insurance companies, banks, mutual funds and hedge funds, based on individual consideration and CAMEL models.

## · Construction Credit Analyst at Bank of Bogotá

June 2015 - May 2017

#### Responsibilities:

- Analysis of credit lending for construction companies for specific housing and commercial projects, through study of financial statements and future cash flows.
- Analysis of viability of construction projects in different cities considering local market conditions.
- Structuring of construction project financing through trust contracts.

## Intern at the Presidency of the Republic of Colombia

January to July 2014

## Responsibilities:

 Managing databases of national infrastructure projects and producing detailed presentations with analysis of their progress.

# **EDUCATION**

#### Msc in Finance

Tilburg University, The Netherlands. August 2018 – Expected graduation approx. August 2019.

#### **BA in Economics**

Universidad del Rosario, Bogotá, Colombia. Graduated in October 2014 – GPA 4.16 / 5.0

#### **Double degree in Economics**

Université de Toulouse 1, Toulouse, France. Graduated in 2013 with a mention "assez-bien" for above average GPA.

## LANGUAGE SKILLS

Spanish: Native language

• English: Professional working proficiency

Obtained a score of 106/120 in the TOEFL test in February 2018. Obtained C1 level in the Michigan English Test in July 2014.

• French: Professional working proficiency

Obtained B2 level in the DELF exam in 2010

Dutch: A1 level

Two one-semester courses in Tilburg University between Aug 2018 – Apr 2019.

# **COMPUTER SKILLS**

- Excellent knowledge of the Microsoft Office suite, specially Microsoft Excel and Visual Basic for Excel macros.
- Experience working with Stata and the R software for statistics.
- Knowledge of computer programming in Python and web technologies such as Javascript/CSS.

## **ACADEMIC HIGHLIGHTS**

- Selected for the Double Degree Program with the University of Toulouse after passing a series
  of tests in economics and French proficiency.
- Scholarship in Universidad del Rosario for obtaining a high score in the ICFES test (national examination) and for maintaining a GPA above 4/5 for all semesters of the undergraduate degree.
- Best score in the ICFES (standardized test) of high school class.